Greg Arnold

New Philadelphia, Ohio | 330-204-0860 | garnold.805@gmail.com gregarnold.dev
LinkedIn | GitHub | SoundCloud

SUMMARY

GIS professional with experience in energy & utility industry, autonomous vehicle development. Experience includes GPS data collection, map creation, and geodatabase management. Recent software development experience includes full-stack software development. This new exposure has confirmed my interest in software development and programming. Career desire has shifted to utilize and advance my new software development skills and knowledge to become more involved in projects like autonomous vehicle development and/or software application development.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

V for Vehicle - Github | Demo

React and Ruby on Rails single page app for car shopping

- Rails 7 with React & Esbuild. Login and navigation flow via react-router-dom V6.
- Frontend leveraged with Material-UI, backend through Active Record and PostgreSQL.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Giffen Solutions, Inc. (DBA MedXCom) – Jr Software Developer Hilliard, OH (Remote)

09/2020 - 07/2021

- Full stack Ruby on Rails medical communication web application development
- Involved in Agile software development team; weekly organization meetings to keep on track with demands of leadership and the needs of
 application improvements for patients and doctors. Biweekly development team meetings to keep track of sprints.
- Added 3rd party Daily.co video conferencing app integration, enabling patients and doctors to video call directly in app. TDD (Test Driven Development), added features with front end HTML and CSS, and backend links to connect appropriate doctor to patient.
- Tested application to ensure uninterrupted functionality with new AthenaHealth API changes
- Added automated one-click feature to help support staff with customer turnover; account deactivation, Plivo phone number un-renting.
- Processed and updated custom voice recording prompts utilizing Audacity and AWS

Team Fishel - CAD Technician

Columbus, OH

05/2020 - 07/2020

- Assisted in aerial and underground 5G fiber network design and route optimization with AutoCAD Civil 3D 2020
- Produced plan & profile engineering drawings utilizing utility shapefiles and LiDAR data processed through AutoCAD ReCap.
- Created construction and traffic control maps to assist field crew during network installation.

NiSource – GIS Analyst

Columbus, OH

10/2018 - 02/2020

- Managed and updated gas pipeline network GIS database using ArcGIS
- Contributed to development of GPS Program project management; participated in weekly team meetings to continuously shape GPS QA standards to optimize both vendor field collection and internal QA procedures to meet monthly deadlines.

Uber ATG – Map Production Specialist

Pittsburgh, PA

10/2016 - 05/2018

- Produced maps for Uber's self-driving vehicles using proprietary software on Linux workstations.
- Speeds team member; Updated and managed speed limit GIS database with QGIS. Practiced scripting to bulk apply speed limits to maps. Continuously optimized scripts to reduce execution time and minimize manual cleanup on maps after script runs.
- QA team member; Reviewed maps in final step before live use in vehicles. Monitored common map QA/QC issues and accordingly made suggestions to update mapping standards

First Energy - GIS Technician

Greensburg, PA

01/2016 - 10/2016

Managed and updated electric distribution system GIS database

The Ohio State University – Student Employee

Columbus, OH

09/2015 - 12/2015

Food, Agricultural and Biological Engineering Precision Agriculture program; assisted in maintenance & research

Bair Goodie & Associates – CAD/GIS Technician

New Philadelphia, OH

12/2014 - 02/2015

Produced AEP power line plan & profile drawings, created Right of Way & As-built maps

Kimble Companies – GIS/Survey Technician

Dover, OH

08/2014 - 11/2014

Created maps for internal planning. Conducted landfill and mine surveys. Managed oil well geodatabase

SKILLS

Proficient: ArcGIS, AutoCAD, GPS data QA/QC, Microsoft Office

Experience: Ruby (Ruby on Rails), JavaScript, Python, Agile Management, Test Driven Development, Jest, HTML, CSS, SQL, JSON,

Cloudflare, Docker, Ansible

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac OS X, Linux Ubuntu Other Skills: Land surveying; conventional and RTK, Audacity

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH – 05/2014

Flatiron School, Online – 07/2022

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Science Software Engineering

LANGUAGES

Basic Spanish